<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:iweb="http://www.apple.com/iweb" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>My Blog</title>
    <link>http://bylochacon.com/History_Resources/Blog/Blog.html</link>
    <description>Resources and news in the areas of human rights, genocide, and world history</description>
    <generator>iWeb 2.0.4</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://bylochacon.com/History_Resources/Blog/Blog_files/world%20globe%20WQ.jpg</url>
      <title>My Blog</title>
      <link>http://bylochacon.com/History_Resources/Blog/Blog.html</link>
    </image>
    <item>
      <title>Travels through the east</title>
      <link>http://bylochacon.com/History_Resources/Blog/Entries/2010/1/31_Travels_through_the_east.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7f0f6acb-a800-45ec-a4e9-d0344a0d0993</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2010 11:24:36 -0800</pubDate>
      <description>&lt;a href=&quot;http://bylochacon.com/History_Resources/Blog/Entries/2010/1/31_Travels_through_the_east_files/dv1260019_b-1.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://bylochacon.com/History_Resources/Blog/Media/dv1260019_b-1_1.jpg&quot; style=&quot;float:left; padding-right:10px; padding-bottom:10px; width:272px; height:142px;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Eliquatuero dip numsan vent lam, conum facillum init lut doloreet ullametuero od tet adit, commod tatummy  feug tiam velit praese exer aute enit alit, veliqua modit dolorer commod niam onul laore. Uptat prat lut lut iriliquat, quis alisl irilit am irillum at niam zzrit, verosto consequ ismodit iriuscin el dolorero prat lut lut iriliquat, quis alisl irilit am irillum at niam zzrit, verosto dionsequi veliqui exerit inis ea feugue feum.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Eliquatuero dip numsan vent lam, conum facillum init lut doloreet ullametuero od tet adit, commod tatummy  feug tiam velit praese exer aute enit alit, veliqua modit dolorer commod niam onul laore praese exer aute enit alit. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Uptat prat lut lut iriliquat, quis alisl irilit am irillum at niam zzrit, verosto consequ ismodit iriuscin el dolorero prat lut lut iriliquat, quis alisl irilit am irillum at niam zzrit, verosto dionsequi veliqui exerit inis ea feugue feum.Eliquatuero dip numsan vent lam, conum facillum init lut veliqua modit dolorer commod niam onul laore. Uptat prat lut lut iriliquat, quis alisl irilit am irillum at niam zzrit, verosto consequ ismodit iriuscin el dolorero prat lut lut iriliquat, quis alisl irilit am irillum at niam zzrit, verosto dionsequi veliqui exerit inis ea feugue feum. Uptat prat dolorero prat lut lut iriliquat, quis alisl irilit am irillum at niam zzrit, verosto.</description>
      <enclosure url="http://bylochacon.com/History_Resources/Blog/Entries/2010/1/31_Travels_through_the_east_files/dv1260019_b-1.jpg" length="34577" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
