<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="F4746D59-F999-41D9-83FC-91C87BC93810">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20120420" date="2012-04-20 20:24:34 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-header-attribute" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>BLOG</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="5_Plan_of_attack_files/shapeimage_1.jpg" left="0px" top="0px" width="393px" height="210px"/>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>I have never really followed through on setting up a website before, but I think that this could be a good way for me to get my head around the myriad of resources available to students of history and human rights.  I am not teaching right now, and I am not currently enrolled as a student, so I want to make sure that my brain isn&#x2019;t complete mush when I apply to programs in the fall.  &#xD;&#xD;First I set up all the areas I wanted on the site, and then realized I bit off way more than I could chew - initially, at least.  This project will indeed take many months.  Its already been four weeks of fairly focused work to get it to this point.&#xD;&#xD;My goal is to finish all of the Rwandan Genocide sections before the end of next week, when I go down to visit my family in Ventura for a few days.  So far, the film section is ready to post, as is one of a possible sixteen bibliographies.  Just typing that makes me realize I may need more than another week.  Links are also a challenge - how much information should be on a site before I include it?  Which sites are most valid?  When should I say &#x2018;enough is enough&#x2019;, and end the list?  I suppose those are things I will have to figure out in the next week!</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>Plan of Attack</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Friday, March 5, 2010&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
</content>
