<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="F4746D59-F999-41D9-83FC-91C87BC93810">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20110901" date="2011-09-01 20:17:32 -0700"/>
  <textBox id="generic-header-attribute" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>BLOG</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="9_New_Site_additions_files/shapeimage_1.jpg" left="0px" top="0px" width="395px" height="210px"/>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>They deal with the experiences and study of Jehovah&#x2019;s Witnesses during the Holocaust brought to my attention by another H-Net listserv participant, Sandra Milakovich of the Arnold Liebster Foundation.  The site is &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.alst.org/"&gt;http://www.alst.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;.  I am adding it to my &lt;a href="perma://BLPageReference/8E8C569E-794D-4FA8-9414-1538282D56E1"&gt;links for Holocaust information&lt;/a&gt;.  Here is what she wrote me:  &#xD;&#xD;&lt;i&gt;&#x201C;I'd like to recommend the addition of an educational resource for teachers and students on the Nazi persecution of Jehovah's Witnesses at&#xA0;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.alst.org/"&gt;http://www.alst.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;. The site is available in English, Spanish, French, German and Italian. The Arnold-Liebster Foundation, established by Holocaust-era survivors Max Liebster and Simone Arnold Liebster in January 2002, announced this new resource to The Association of Holocaust Organizations in 2007. Many Holocaust Institutions have added&#xA0;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;a href="http://alst.org/"&gt;alst.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;&#xA0;to their links page, including United States Holocaust Memorial Museum, Holocaust Center of Northern California, Shoah Foundation, Facing History and Ourselves, CANDLES Holocaust Museum, The Holocaust Chronicle, Jewish Virtual Library, Holocaust Museum Houston, Florida Holocaust Museum, Illinois Holocaust Museum &amp; Education Center, Virginia Holocaust Museum, and NorthWest Center for Holocaust Genocide &amp; Ethnocide Education.&#x201D;&#xD;&#xD;&lt;/i&gt;Sandra also suggested a book and a film which I will add at a later date.  I am putting the information she provided below for now:  &#xD;&lt;i&gt;&#x201C;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Facing the Lion - Memoirs of a Young Girl in Nazi Europe&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;i&gt;&#xA0;by Simone Arnold Liebster&#xD;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;Facing the Lion is the autobiographical account of a young girl's faith and courage. Set during the Nazi occupation of Eastern France, it tells the story of one 12-year-old's struggle to follow her conscience rather than give in to Nazi propaganda and persecution. Simone's honesty about her joys and fears and her harrowing experiences at school and in a Nazi prison have appealed to thousands of readers, many of whom are young people themselves, struggling with similar peer pressure today.&#xA0;&#xD;Available in unabridged and abridged editions, English and Spanish&#xD;Appropriate for middle and high school students&#xD;Free downloadable Study Guides&#xA0;at&#xA0;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.alst.org/pages-us/education/study-guides.html"&gt;http://www.alst.org/pages-us/education/study-guides.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;&#xD;Free interactive Skype conference with author&#xA0;at&#xA0;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.alst.org/pages-us/education/interactive-videoconference.html"&gt;http://www.alst.org/pages-us/education/interactive-videoconference.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;&#xD;&#xD;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Jehovah's Witnesses Stand Firm Against Nazi Assault&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;i&gt;&#xA0;&#xA0;28-minute Classroom Edition Documentary DVD with Study Guide available in English and Spanish&#xD;As the Nazi killing machine engulfed Europe with terror, thousands of Jehovah's Witnesses suffered brutal persecution. In this DVD, 10 historians from Europe and North America, and more than 20 Witness survivors, join in relating a story of courage and triumph that must be told.&#xA0;&#xA0;56-page Study Guide includes lesson plan, activities, survivor profiles with discussion questions, selected readings, glossary, chronology and transcript.&#xD;Appropriate for middle and high school students&#xD;Available from United States Holocaust Memorial Museum Book Shop at&#xA0;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.ushmm.org/"&gt;www.ushmm.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt; and from Reed Presentations, Inc. (Contact Sandra at&#xA0;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;800-774-1599 x 121&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;)&#x201D;&lt;/i&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>Jehovah&#x2019;s Witness Additions</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Saturday, July 9, 2011&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
</content>
