<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="F4746D59-F999-41D9-83FC-91C87BC93810">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20100412" date="2010-04-12 11:00:18 -0700"/>
  <textBox id="generic-header-attribute" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>BLOG</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="12_What%E2%80%99s_Working_files/shapeimage_1.jpg" left="0px" top="0px" width="395px" height="210px"/>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>I have been haphazard in my entries here.  It is still a strange feeling to be journaling about a project in a public format.  So, until I have developed more of an idea of what I want to say, I will just let you know what is working on the site.&#xD;&#xD;Okay, here is a list of what on the site actually has content so far (I will update you with new additions through this blog as they are completed):&#xD;Homepage, &#x201C;Our World&#x201D;&#xD;Links (lists of what will be linked there)&#xD;Films (lists of what will be linked there)&#xD;Bibliographies (lists of what will be linked there)&#xD;Blog&#xD;About Me&#xD;Groups (podcasts and youtube have nothing, the rest have links but no descriptions)&#xD;Events (just five initial organizations)&#xD;Causes&#xD;Support&#xD;Bibliographies of the Rwandan Genocide (what will be linked there)&#xD;Bibliographies of the Holocaust (what will be linked there)&#xD;Links Regarding East Asia (links only, no descriptions yet)&#xD;Links Regarding India &amp; South Asia (links only, no descriptions yet)&#xD;Bibliography of Politicide in the USSR&#xD;Bibliography of the Armenian Genocide&#xD;Bibliography of Personal Accounts of the Rwandan Genocide&#xD;Bibliography of Overviews of the Rwandan Genocide&#xD;Bibliography of Comparative and Introductions to Genocide&#xD;Bibliography of Genocide &amp; Imperialism&#xD;Bibliography of Genocide &amp; War&#xD;Bibliography of Genocide &amp; Social Revolution&#xD;Bibliography of Genocide &amp; Indigenous Peoples&#xD;Bibliography of Introductions to the Holocaust&#xD;Films Dealing with the Rwandan Genocide&#xD;Films Dealing with the French Revolution&#xD;Films Dealing with Genocide in Darfur&#xD;Films Dealing with Genocide in General&#xD;Films Dealing with Genocide in East Timor&#xD;Films Dealing with Ethnic Cleansing in the former Yugoslavia&#xD;Films Dealing with Armenian Genocide&#xD;Films Dealing with Cambodian Genocide&#xD;Films Dealing with the Cold War&#xD;Films Dealing with the USSR&#xD;Films Dealing with World War II&#xD;Films Dealing with the Holocaust&#xD;Links Regarding Comparative &amp; General Genocide&#xD;Links for Teacher Training and Teacher Organizations&#xD;Links Regarding the Rwandan Genocide&#xD;Links Regarding Human Rights and Women&#xD;Links Regarding Africa&#xD;Links for Websites by Teachers&#xD;Links for Maps and General Reference&#xD;Links by Geographic &amp; Cultural Areas&#xD;Links for Curriculum &amp; Lectures&#xD;Links for Outlines, Notes &amp; Timelines&#xD;&#xD;Obviously, most of these need additional sources and/or formatting.  And, for some reason, the google search on the bottom of each page does not seem to be working, so I will try and figure out what is happening and fix it.&#xD;&#xD;I have a ton of personal stuff to get done this week, like repairing my poor old corolla from its third break-in attempt this year, and trying to get some daytime sleep since my little girl is not so interested in doing that at night, but my goal is to get an introductory bibliography to the Holocaust done, to read, and to study for the GRE.  I&#x2019;m hoping that if I write it all here I will feel more accountable and stay on top of everything!&#xD;&#xD;I want to thank Adam Jones, author of many books on genocide, for the invaluable lists of sources for further study and films on genocide war that he provides online and in his textbook, Genocide: A Comprehensive Introduction.  These have become my starting place, and I am adding these sources to my lists first, to be built on later by myself and contributions you make.</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>What&#x2019;s Working</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Monday, April 12, 2010&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
</content>
