<?xml version="1.0"?>
<content collectionGUID="F4746D59-F999-41D9-83FC-91C87BC93810">
  <lastEdited clientType="local-build-20120504" date="2012-05-04 23:05:33 +0000"/>
  <textBox id="generic-header-attribute" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>BLOG</richText>
  </textBox>
  <image id="generic-picture-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes" src="26_Book_Notes%3A__The_World_That_Trade_Created_files/shapeimage_1.jpg" left="0px" top="0px" width="393px" height="210px"/>
  <textBox id="generic-body-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>A while back I needed to distill the main points of this book to present in a course I was taking - I thought I&#x2019;d share them here. (To download these notes as a pdf, click here:  &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="World%2520Trade%2520Created%2520Notes%2520Organizer.pdf"&gt;World Trade Created Notes Organizer.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;)&#xD;&#xD;&lt;b&gt;Pomeranz, Kenneth, and Steven Topik. The World That Trade Created: Society, Culture, and the World Economy, 1400 to the Present. Armonk, NY: M.E. Sharpe, 2006.&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&#xD;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;1.  Through the Creation of Market Conventions&lt;/b&gt;&#xD;-Economic activities are social acts that bring groups with very different ideas together. &#xD;-Intensification of trade in this period led to increasing agreements on trade conventions. &#xD;-Trade diasporas organized trade until colonialism.&#xD;&#xD;&lt;b&gt;2.  Transport Tactics&lt;/b&gt;&#xD;-Transport costs limited the size of cities.&#xD;-The railroad and steamships brought the world closer together and elevated manufacturers and financiers over merchants. &#xD;-Technology allowed people to keep in touch with home, and ended the necessity of integration.&#xD;&#xD;&lt;b&gt;3.  Economic Culture of Drugs&lt;/b&gt;&#xD;-What has changed over time is not the value, but the definition of drug. &#xD;-Governments eventually legalized many so they could tax them.&#xD;-Colonial empires were built on the foundation of drug trades. &#xD;-Drugs have been both the foundation and bane of states.&#xD;&#xD;&lt;b&gt;4.  Commodities in World Trade&lt;/b&gt;&#xD;-As specific commodities became global, their values and meanings changed from what they had been locally. &#xD;-New global commodities often took on associations antithetical to their natural properties. &#xD;-Consuming societies tried to synthesize replacements and/or transplant them.&#xD;&#xD;&lt;b&gt;5.  Economics of Violence&lt;/b&gt;&#xD;-Relationships between violence and entrepreneurship have always existed. &#xD;-Warfare and economic growth are often not contradictory. &#xD;-Warfare has often been the mother of invention. &#xD;-Financing war without participating is also quite profitable.&#xD;&#xD;&lt;b&gt;6.  Making Modern Markets&lt;/b&gt;&#xD;-For there to be a true world economy, laws and practices have to be predictable and universal. &#xD;-Standardization &amp; impersonal relations were the key.&#xD;-Gold and silver became the money standards. &#xD;-Industrialization has caused people to trust distant logos more than local production.&#xD;&#xD;&lt;b&gt;7.  World Trade, Industrialization &amp; De-Industrialization&lt;/b&gt;&#xD;-Very few countries have instituted free trade. &#xD;-Industrialization in a society depends on a sharp increase in trade. &#xD;-Because industrialization coincided with imperialism, we can never know how much industry-increased trade was lost.&#xD;&#xD;&lt;i&gt;(summary originally created 2006)&lt;/i&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-title-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>Book Notes:  The World That Trade Created</richText>
  </textBox>
  <textBox id="generic-datefield-attributes" dynamic="no" visible="yes">
    <richText>&lt;b&gt;Tuesday, April 26, 2011&lt;/b&gt;</richText>
  </textBox>
</content>
