<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss xmlns:iweb="http://www.apple.com/iweb" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog</title>
    <link>http://bylochacon.com/History_Resources/Blog</link>
    <description>Resources and news in the areas of human rights, genocide, and world history</description>
    <item>
      <title>Genocide of the Herero and Nama</title>
      <link>http://bylochacon.com/History_Resources/Blog/Entries/2010/5/24_Entry_1.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">078a2ef4-a02d-4daf-8154-b676e561f5a5</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 May 2010 12:53:02 -0700</pubDate>
      <description>Between 1904 and 1907, more than half the population of both the Herero and Nama peoples of Namibia were killed by German genocidal imperial tactics, including starvation, forced relocation, and the poisoning of well-water. I have put the few links I have found here:  &lt;a href="../Links_Regarding_the_Genocide_of_the_Herero_%2526_Nama.html"&gt;Links Regarding the Genocide of the Herero &amp;amp; Nama&lt;/a&gt;.  More scholarship is needed.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;I have also added content to the teaching pages below:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="../Links_for_General_Reference.html"&gt;Links for General Reference&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="../Links_for_Student-Friendly_Sites.html"&gt;Links for Student-Friendly Sites&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;More is coming, just as quick as I can.  I am adding a bit to each page and then, when each page has starter content, I plan to cycle back through and flesh them out with more sources.  Someday, I may finally even add my own original work!  </description>
      <iweb:image href="Media/Namibia-Landscape-6346.jpg"></iweb:image>
      <iweb:comment enabled="0" count="0" link="http://bylochacon.com/History_Resources/Blog/Entries/2010/5/24_Entry_1.html#comment_layer"></iweb:comment>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding &amp; Combatting Hate</title>
      <link>http://bylochacon.com/History_Resources/Blog/Entries/2010/5/21_Entry_1.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">f6995248-dfc6-4c60-bfce-ed4b5f4bd99a</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 May 2010 16:43:06 -0700</pubDate>
      <description>I believe education is key to change.  Here are some widely-accepted &lt;a href="../Definitions_of_Hate_Issues.html"&gt;Definitions of Hate Issues&lt;/a&gt;.  I have also just added the links to teacher training for anti-bias classrooms here: &lt;a href="../Teacher_Training_in_Tolerance_%2526_Anti-Bias.html"&gt;Teacher Training in Tolerance &amp;amp; Understanding&lt;/a&gt;.</description>
      <iweb:image href="Media/070205_neonazi_hmed_3p.hmedium.jpg"></iweb:image>
      <iweb:comment enabled="0" count="0" link="http://bylochacon.com/History_Resources/Blog/Entries/2010/5/21_Entry_1.html#comment_layer"></iweb:comment>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Cambodian Genocide</title>
      <link>http://bylochacon.com/History_Resources/Blog/Entries/2010/5/20_The_Cambodian_Genocide.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">fcc19025-d694-43d1-8583-269e06559b36</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 May 2010 11:05:59 -0700</pubDate>
      <description>I have just added links, of which there are many very good, very complete sites, to resources on the Cambodian Genocide.  The book list is already up, as is the films list.  The links with content for Cambodia on this site are below:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="../Cambodian_Genocide.html"&gt;Cambodian Genocide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="../Links_Regarding_the_Cambodian_Genocide.html"&gt;Links Regarding the Cambodian Genocide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="../Bibliography_of_the_Cambodian_Genocide.html"&gt;Bibliography of the Cambodian Genocide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href="../Films_Dealing_with_the_Cambodian_Genocide.html"&gt;Films Dealing with the Cambodian Genocide&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <iweb:image href="Media/angkor-wat-cambodia-garion88.jpg"></iweb:image>
      <iweb:comment enabled="0" count="0" link="http://bylochacon.com/History_Resources/Blog/Entries/2010/5/20_The_Cambodian_Genocide.html#comment_layer"></iweb:comment>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hate Speech, Hate Groups, &amp; Hate Crimes</title>
      <link>http://bylochacon.com/History_Resources/Blog/Entries/2010/5/19_Hate_Speech,_Hate_Groups,_%26_Hate_Crimes.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">b7c7cdc1-fe0d-48e1-88f5-5c0b6c408c1e</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2010 10:22:07 -0700</pubDate>
      <description>A few years ago I saw this guy on a news broadcast as a suspect in a hate crime.  My first thought was, of course he did it - he&#x2019;s so proud of his ideology he tattooed it on his forehead!  Unfortunately, most perpetrators of hate crimes, members of hate groups and participants in hate speech are not so clearly labeled.  &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;A couple weeks ago a man in my apartment building was murdered, beaten and left on the railroad tracks, because he was gay.  A number of years ago I had a transgender student who was killed in a homophobic rage.  A middle school student near my hometown was shot execution-style by another student for being gay.  These are not experiences I researched; they are events that are tangential to my life.  &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;I don&#x2019;t understand how people are threatened by homosexuality.  It doesn&#x2019;t hurt my life or my marriage or my daughter in any way - how does it hurt others?  Why is it so scary?  &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Obviously, homosexuals are not the only targets of hate crimes, speech or language.  My multi-ethnic students could have told hundreds of times they or a friend or family member dealt with bald-faced prejudice. My former student and teacher&#x2019;s aide, David Armstead, is helping me put together information for those hurt by hate, students and teachers.  The topic page is located here:  &lt;a href="../Hate.html"&gt;Hate&lt;/a&gt;, and the first page with content is &lt;a href="../News_of_Hate.html"&gt;News of Hate&lt;/a&gt;.  Please email me with ideas of sites to add.  Thank you.  </description>
      <iweb:image href="Media/tattoo-racist.jpg"></iweb:image>
      <iweb:comment enabled="0" count="0" link="http://bylochacon.com/History_Resources/Blog/Entries/2010/5/19_Hate_Speech,_Hate_Groups,_%26_Hate_Crimes.html#comment_layer"></iweb:comment>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Foundations of the Modern World</title>
      <link>http://bylochacon.com/History_Resources/Blog/Entries/2010/5/13_Foundations_of_the_Modern_World.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">1ce060a6-2bd3-4af4-81a7-dcb22b5e12f6</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 May 2010 10:08:56 -0700</pubDate>
      <description>In California, tenth grade world history courses are usually begun by a review of the foundations of world civilization.  This enormous topic is then  reduced, by necessity, to a quick overview of global religions and a summary of the European Enlightenment.  I have put together a list of books on these topics, on the page &lt;a href="../Bibliography_of_Intellectual_%2526_Ethical_Foundations_of_the_Modern_Era.html"&gt;Bibliography of Intellectual &amp;amp; Ethical Foundations of the Modern Era&lt;/a&gt;, and I plan to add to it more global perspectives as I find them and as they are suggested to me.  </description>
      <iweb:image href="Media/world-religion.jpg"></iweb:image>
      <iweb:comment enabled="0" count="0" link="http://bylochacon.com/History_Resources/Blog/Entries/2010/5/13_Foundations_of_the_Modern_World.html#comment_layer"></iweb:comment>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Globalization in World History</title>
      <link>http://bylochacon.com/History_Resources/Blog/Entries/2010/5/12_Entry_1.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">1fc00a83-89f3-4233-b3e9-fbdb5c6aaac8</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2010 11:06:51 -0700</pubDate>
      <description>There are few words in modern political discussion tossed around more freely and are so misunderstood.  Here is a beginning reading list to get a handle on the enormously popular topic:  &lt;a href="../Bibliography_of_Globalization.html"&gt;Bibliography of Globalization&lt;/a&gt;.</description>
      <iweb:image href="Media/globalization-protest.jpg"></iweb:image>
      <iweb:comment enabled="0" count="0" link="http://bylochacon.com/History_Resources/Blog/Entries/2010/5/12_Entry_1.html#comment_layer"></iweb:comment>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Teaching History</title>
      <link>http://bylochacon.com/History_Resources/Blog/Entries/2010/5/11_Teaching_History.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">386fe50b-c8a4-4521-ba5c-9bebe1be7591</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2010 10:09:55 -0700</pubDate>
      <description>When I was teaching, I spent dozens of hours searching for texts that would help me be a more creative teacher.  I remembered how, as a high school student, I had learned well from lecture, but most of my classmates had not.  I hated how everyone who heard that I taught history said that it had been their least favorite class.  I wanted to be better, to help students see the impact of history on our daily lives, the danger of ignorance, and how crucial history was to understanding so many other disciplines.  History has the drama that can be found in literature, the logic that can be found in science, and the creativity that can be found in writing and arguing.  I&#x2019;ve put together a list of texts that will hopefully be of use to other world history teachers here:  &lt;a href="../Bibliography_of_Teaching_History.html"&gt;Bibliography of Teaching History&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;I&#x2019;ve also updated the descriptions on the page &lt;a href="../Links_for_Teacher_Training_%2526_Organizations.html"&gt;Links for Teacher Training &amp;amp; Organizations&lt;/a&gt; to reflect my experiences with each.  These are definitely the best!</description>
      <iweb:image href="Media/eduCommons%20globe.jpg"></iweb:image>
      <iweb:comment enabled="0" count="0" link="http://bylochacon.com/History_Resources/Blog/Entries/2010/5/11_Teaching_History.html#comment_layer"></iweb:comment>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Commodity Histories</title>
      <link>http://bylochacon.com/History_Resources/Blog/Entries/2010/5/10_Entry_1.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">b3e2df77-4319-4bb3-9557-12d4477f5544</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2010 10:05:59 -0700</pubDate>
      <description>I love commodity and thematic histories.  These are the books that you can read and learn about economics, culture, individuals, groups, international and domestic politics, changing tastes, status symbols, classes, science . . . the list goes on.  The page &lt;a href="../Bibliography_of_Thematic_%2526_Commodity_Histories.html"&gt;Bibliography of Thematic &amp;amp; Commodity Histories&lt;/a&gt; has a list of books on topics including salt, diamonds and oil, among many others.  </description>
      <iweb:image href="Media/conflict%20diamond%20hand.jpg"></iweb:image>
      <iweb:comment enabled="0" count="0" link="http://bylochacon.com/History_Resources/Blog/Entries/2010/5/10_Entry_1.html#comment_layer"></iweb:comment>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bangladesh Genocide</title>
      <link>http://bylochacon.com/History_Resources/Blog/Entries/2010/5/7_Bangladesh_Genocide.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">404e1a13-8a23-4131-ad20-b5ac23aed447</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 7 May 2010 10:20:35 -0700</pubDate>
      <description>In 1971, a genocide started that claimed up to three million people, though estimates range as low as 200,000.  Eight to ten million others fled the country to find safety.  A short starting list is here:  &lt;a href="../Bibliography_of_the_Bangladesh_Genocide.html"&gt;Bibliography of the Bangladesh Genocide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br/&gt;(On a side note, with the posting of this page, all of the bibliographies dealing with genocide and mass murder now have initial content on them.  Yay!)</description>
      <iweb:image href="Media/bangladesh.jpg"></iweb:image>
      <iweb:comment enabled="0" count="0" link="http://bylochacon.com/History_Resources/Blog/Entries/2010/5/7_Bangladesh_Genocide.html#comment_layer"></iweb:comment>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>East Timor</title>
      <link>http://bylochacon.com/History_Resources/Blog/Entries/2010/5/6_East_Timor.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">82f010f6-89b7-4ac5-aacb-869be100dbb2</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 6 May 2010 12:25:29 -0700</pubDate>
      <description>Indonesia occupied East Timor from 1975 until 1999, with final realization of independence in 2002.  Torture, starvation, massacre and summary executions were suffered for twenty five years.  Out of a population of less than one-million, the East Timorese are estimated to have lost more than 100,000.  A short reading list can be found on the &lt;a href="../Bibliography_of_the_Genocide_in_East_Timor.html"&gt;Bibliography of the East Timor Genocide&lt;/a&gt; page.</description>
      <iweb:image href="Media/EastTimor%20600x389.jpg"></iweb:image>
      <iweb:comment enabled="0" count="0" link="http://bylochacon.com/History_Resources/Blog/Entries/2010/5/6_East_Timor.html#comment_layer"></iweb:comment>
    </item>
    <iweb:dateFormat>EEEE, MMMM d, yyyy</iweb:dateFormat>
    <iweb:baseURL>http://bylochacon.com/History_Resources/Blog</iweb:baseURL>
    <iweb:maximumSummaryItems>10</iweb:maximumSummaryItems>
  </channel>
</rss>
