<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:iweb="http://www.apple.com/iweb" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>My Blog</title>
    <link>http://bylochacon.com/History_Resources/Blog/Blog.html</link>
    <description>Resources and news in the areas of world history, genocide and teaching.</description>
    <generator>iWeb 2.0.4</generator>
    <image>
      <url>http://bylochacon.com/History_Resources/Blog/Blog_files/world%20globe%20WQ.jpg</url>
      <title>My Blog</title>
      <link>http://bylochacon.com/History_Resources/Blog/Blog.html</link>
    </image>
    <item>
      <title>Book Review:  The King Took Flight</title>
      <link>http://bylochacon.com/History_Resources/Blog/Entries/2011/4/21_Book_Review%3A__The_King_Took_Flight.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">6f5c1dda-b76e-4b88-b6c8-2931032b7244</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2011 10:43:31 -0700</pubDate>
      <description>&lt;a href=&quot;http://bylochacon.com/History_Resources/Blog/Entries/2011/4/21_Book_Review%3A__The_King_Took_Flight_files/tackett-kingtookflight.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://bylochacon.com/History_Resources/Blog/Media/tackett-kingtookflight_1.jpg&quot; style=&quot;float:left; padding-right:10px; padding-bottom:10px; width:271px; height:271px;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Tackett, Timothy.  When the King Took Flight.  Harvard University Press:  Cambridge, Massachusetts.  2003.&lt;br/&gt;	Timothy Tackett is an accomplished and well-recognized historian of the French Revolution.  He has opposed ideological interpretations of the revolution and instead emphasized that the route the Revolution took was not inevitable, but instead contingent on the myriad of events and decisions that influenced everything that came after.  The focus of his scholarship in the past has been the Civil Constitution of the Clergy and the politics of the Constituent Assembly; here he focuses on the seemingly narrow event of the king’s failed escape and links it to the larger topic of the change from the more peaceful, more liberal course of the early revolution to the bloody, paranoid path of the Terror.  &lt;br/&gt;	When the King Took Flight takes the single event of the royal families failed attempt at escaping France and explains how it changed the probable direction of the revolution.  It begins at the moment of capture, late at night on June 21, 1791 in the small border town of Varennes.  There, the royal entourage was stopped only two hours shy of their destination by small town folk who would have, in an earlier time, never questioned the king, let alone ended his journey.  This change in respect for the king, from divine authority to human, came directly from the recent events of the first two years of revolution.  Citizens had been involved with, and kept abreast of events in the Revolution, such as the calling of the Estates General, the creation of the National Assembly, the ability to petition the government, and the process of creating a constitution.  Having participated in the transformation of the nation had raised expectations and instilled a feeling of national identity and self-confidence.  The newfound confidence of the inhabitants of Varennes is what made it possible for a tanner, a grocer and a judge to inform the king that he would be permitted to go no further.  &lt;br/&gt;	The development of the plot to flee had its origins in the October days.  The Queen was fully convinced that the crowd that forced her family to move to the Tuileries palace had fully intended to kill her that day, and she had no intention of supporting their reforms or staying in revolutionary Paris.  Marie-Antoinette held considerable political sway, at first because of her ability to make or break the careers of various ministers, and later because her perpetually indecisive husband relied heavily on her decision-making abilities.  The king agreed that they needed to leave, but in his characteristically slow and vacillating way, he continued to put off the escape for months.  Everything was ready by early May of 1791, and one of the Queen’s servants had caught wind of the plan by early June, but the date they actually left was in late June.  &lt;br/&gt;	Escaping took detailed planning, but also a good amount of good fortune.  There were two thousand servants at the palace, and extra guards at the gate since the rumors of escape had been floating around since the servant had guessed correctly at what was being plotted.  The family was disguised, but despite the extreme care taken in many details, the king and queen refused to stop certain telling behaviors.  Marie-Antoinette did not pack lightly, but instead brought along a full wardrobe, a complete make-up kit, some furniture and her hairdresser.  Louis however was probably most to blame for their ultimate capture, as he rode with the windows uncovered, got out at every stop and made conversation with the locals.  He was quickly recognized, as early as one-fourth of the way to the border, because of these sloppy habits.  &lt;br/&gt;	After the speedy one-day to Varennes, the family was forced to travel back to Paris at an achingly slow pace, arriving four days later.  Awed peasants, some who hurled insults at the queen but reserved judgment against the king accompanied the entire trip.  When they arrived in Paris, the tone changed.  There were no more cries of “Long Live the King”, and far fewer hats removed from heads.   The royal guardsmen were pelted with feces and rocks and had to be saved from lynching.  &lt;br/&gt;	Across France, the news had a traumatic effect on the population.  One newspaper, Le babillard (the Chatterer) wrote, “Never has Paris been both so touched with emotion and so calm.  The common people in particular have remained orderly.” (p. 95).  When Louis returned, the mood changed.  Parisians (they were the first to receive copies) read for themselves Louis’ traitorous letter he had left on his desk.  Old respect and pardons for the monarchy were gone.  One telling example was a sign posted outside of the Tuleries soon after, “A large pig has escaped form the premises.  Anyone finding him is urged to return him to his pen.” (p. 104).  &lt;br/&gt;	This betrayal by their king had an immediate effect on a wider acceptance of republicanism.  The National Assembly tried at first to keep the constitution that included the king, and indeed had him sign it, but it failed within the year because of Louis’ continued two-timing.  In the interim, the period between his capture and his beheading, paranoia grew at a fantastic rate.  The use of the word ‘suspect’ greatly increased in administrative documents.  Clergy and nobility became targets of blanket oppression.  Guilt by association and guilt by suspicion became the norm.  Conspiracies took hold of the imagination.  &lt;br/&gt;	In telling this adventure, Tackett argues that the revolution, and indeed all history, is contingent on events and reactions, and not predestined in accordance with any particular ideology.  He reminds readers that there was considerable unity among citizens during the days that they believed that the king was gone, and that the work of the assembly until the capture of the king and upheld the ideals of tolerance, liberty, rights and rule of law.  The king’s abandonment was not only devastating to the French people, especially at the crucial moment of the near-completion of the constitution, it was destabilizing to the state and to society.  &lt;br/&gt;	Tackett makes his work accessible to an audience that is wider than Revolutionary specialists.  He uses a writing style that is readable, focused and interesting. Tackett describes, explains and provides background to events without condescension.  At times it seems this historian’s goal is to explain well enough to teach his University of California undergraduate students, a group he lists in his acknowledgments. &lt;br/&gt;In addition to his easy style, Tackett should be praised for his extensive use of primary and secondary sources, including especially correspondence, newspapers and memoirs. He adds them to his writing seamlessly, not dropped clumsily in the middle of a chapter with a detailed and distracting analysis.  His inclusion adds to understanding and does not clutter his writing.  It should also be recognized that Tackett added several illustrations and cartoons that highlight key moments in the drama of the flight of the king.  Each one was placed with purpose and illuminated the written point.  &lt;br/&gt;	There are few criticisms that have been made of this work.  One reviewer argued that primary importance to readability instead of showing off his meticulous research.  This, however, should not be viewed as a weakness, but as a strength.  The discipline of history is about the spread of knowledge and understanding, accessibility should be an essential aspect of good historical writing.  Tackett’s dedication to teaching is clear throughout – he even thanks his undergraduate students in his acknowledgements – and should be looked at as the model for good historical writing, and not an aberration.&lt;br/&gt;(original, Fall 2005)</description>
      <enclosure url="http://bylochacon.com/History_Resources/Blog/Entries/2011/4/21_Book_Review%3A__The_King_Took_Flight_files/tackett-kingtookflight.jpg" length="56364" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>French Revolution Overviews</title>
      <link>http://bylochacon.com/History_Resources/Blog/Entries/2011/4/20_Entry_1.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">7d64dead-cd31-4e1c-b078-488f198bdcd5</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2011 11:15:20 -0700</pubDate>
      <description>&lt;a href=&quot;http://bylochacon.com/History_Resources/Blog/Entries/2011/4/20_Entry_1_files/french-revolution-women.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://bylochacon.com/History_Resources/Blog/Media/french-revolution-women_1.jpg&quot; style=&quot;float:left; padding-right:10px; padding-bottom:10px; width:271px; height:203px;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Here are some books to get started on studying the French Revolution.  I’m also including my first book review in this section.  &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;../Bibliography_of_Overviews_of_the_French_Revolution.html&quot;&gt;Bibliography of Overviews of the French Revolution&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="http://bylochacon.com/History_Resources/Blog/Entries/2011/4/20_Entry_1_files/french-revolution-women.jpg" length="42211" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Overviews of European Imperialism</title>
      <link>http://bylochacon.com/History_Resources/Blog/Entries/2011/4/18_Overviews_of_European_Imperialism.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">d851999b-9d9c-40b2-bd66-aaa65f2e0427</guid>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2011 15:17:04 -0700</pubDate>
      <description>&lt;a href=&quot;http://bylochacon.com/History_Resources/Blog/Entries/2011/4/18_Overviews_of_European_Imperialism_files/imperialism.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://bylochacon.com/History_Resources/Blog/Media/imperialism_1.jpg&quot; style=&quot;float:left; padding-right:10px; padding-bottom:10px; width:271px; height:281px;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Books to start learning about European Imperialism.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;../Bibliography_of_Overviews_of_Imperialism.html&quot;&gt;Bibliography of Overviews of Imperialism&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;../Bibliographies_of_Imperialism.html&quot;&gt;Bibliographies of Imperialism&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="http://bylochacon.com/History_Resources/Blog/Entries/2011/4/18_Overviews_of_European_Imperialism_files/imperialism.jpg" length="45917" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Overviews of the Great War</title>
      <link>http://bylochacon.com/History_Resources/Blog/Entries/2011/4/17_Overviews_of_the_Great_War.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">241e2abd-f749-4856-8416-2a1641afb93d</guid>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2011 14:20:32 -0700</pubDate>
      <description>&lt;a href=&quot;http://bylochacon.com/History_Resources/Blog/Entries/2011/4/17_Overviews_of_the_Great_War_files/wwi.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://bylochacon.com/History_Resources/Blog/Media/wwi_1.jpg&quot; style=&quot;float:left; padding-right:10px; padding-bottom:10px; width:271px; height:188px;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Here are some books to start learning about the Great War.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;../Bibliography_of_Overviews_of_the_Great_War.html&quot;&gt;Bibliography of Overviews of the Great War&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;../Bibliographies_of_the_Great_War.html&quot;&gt;Bibliographies of the Great War&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="http://bylochacon.com/History_Resources/Blog/Entries/2011/4/17_Overviews_of_the_Great_War_files/wwi.jpg" length="197713" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Overviews of Industrialization</title>
      <link>http://bylochacon.com/History_Resources/Blog/Entries/2011/4/12_Overviews_of_Industrialization.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">1f8a028a-3065-4cff-b349-65411d7533eb</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2011 13:50:19 -0700</pubDate>
      <description>&lt;a href=&quot;http://bylochacon.com/History_Resources/Blog/Entries/2011/4/12_Overviews_of_Industrialization_files/krup_industrial_revolution.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://bylochacon.com/History_Resources/Blog/Media/krup_industrial_revolution_1.jpg&quot; style=&quot;float:left; padding-right:10px; padding-bottom:10px; width:271px; height:182px;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;I am sorry to have been slow in adding content - I was lucky enough to travel a lot in the last six weeks and am just getting my first shot at the computer now.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Here is a handful of books to get started with.  &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;../Bibliography_of_Overviews_of_Industrialization.html&quot;&gt;Bibliography of Overviews of the Industrial Age&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;../Bibliographies_of_Industrialization.html&quot;&gt;Bibliographies of Industrialization&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="http://bylochacon.com/History_Resources/Blog/Entries/2011/4/12_Overviews_of_Industrialization_files/krup_industrial_revolution.jpg" length="50349" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World War II Overviews Bibliography</title>
      <link>http://bylochacon.com/History_Resources/Blog/Entries/2011/3/25_World_War_II_Overviews_Bibliography.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">83107f6d-4fd2-4c31-9426-d72195e8c601</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2011 10:40:28 -0700</pubDate>
      <description>&lt;a href=&quot;http://bylochacon.com/History_Resources/Blog/Entries/2011/3/25_World_War_II_Overviews_Bibliography_files/Chapel%20Hill%20Veterans%20Recall%20World%20War%20II.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://bylochacon.com/History_Resources/Blog/Media/Chapel%20Hill%20Veterans%20Recall%20World%20War%20II_1.jpg&quot; style=&quot;float:left; padding-right:10px; padding-bottom:10px; width:271px; height:277px;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Due to the size of the topic, there will be a series of bibliographies here.  Today is only the start, a selection of introductions to World War II.  &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;../Bibliography_of_World_War_II_Overviews.html&quot;&gt;Bibliography of World War II Overviews&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;../Bibliographies_of_World_War_II.html&quot;&gt;Bibliographies of World War II&lt;/a&gt; (this page will link to the multiple bibliographies posted in the future)</description>
      <enclosure url="http://bylochacon.com/History_Resources/Blog/Entries/2011/3/25_World_War_II_Overviews_Bibliography_files/Chapel%20Hill%20Veterans%20Recall%20World%20War%20II.jpg" length="121226" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cold War Bibliography</title>
      <link>http://bylochacon.com/History_Resources/Blog/Entries/2011/3/23_Cold_War_Bibliography.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">54e19ee6-7ca9-4130-9781-b2338990853f</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Mar 2011 11:48:08 -0700</pubDate>
      <description>&lt;a href=&quot;http://bylochacon.com/History_Resources/Blog/Entries/2011/3/23_Cold_War_Bibliography_files/atomicblast.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://bylochacon.com/History_Resources/Blog/Media/atomicblast_1.jpg&quot; style=&quot;float:left; padding-right:10px; padding-bottom:10px; width:271px; height:203px;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The vastness of the geography, ideology, politics, science and time affected by the Cold War requires several bibliographies.  Here is a list of introductions and overviews to the subject.  &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;../Bibliography_of_Cold_War_Overviews.html&quot;&gt;Bibliography of Cold War Overviews&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="http://bylochacon.com/History_Resources/Blog/Entries/2011/3/23_Cold_War_Bibliography_files/atomicblast.jpg" length="24825" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Commodity and Thematic Histories       (&amp; the Links are Done!)</title>
      <link>http://bylochacon.com/History_Resources/Blog/Entries/2011/2/22_Commodity_and_Thematic_Histories_______%28%26_the_Links_are_Done%21%29.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">07b214f0-00cd-4f2a-b2d6-25139d99618e</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2011 10:07:49 -0800</pubDate>
      <description>&lt;a href=&quot;http://bylochacon.com/History_Resources/Blog/Entries/2011/2/22_Commodity_and_Thematic_Histories_______%28%26_the_Links_are_Done%21%29_files/portuguese-wine-history-1.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://bylochacon.com/History_Resources/Blog/Media/portuguese-wine-history-1_1.jpg&quot; style=&quot;float:left; padding-right:10px; padding-bottom:10px; width:271px; height:167px;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Looking at one general theme is an interesting and relatively easy way to get a handle on larger, global histories.  Here are some links to get started: &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;../Links_for_Thematic_%2526_Commodity_Histories.html&quot;&gt;Links for Thematic &amp;amp; Commodity Histories&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;This is an exciting post for me, in that I now have completed posting initial content to all the sub-topics for both &lt;a href=&quot;../Links.html&quot;&gt;Links&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;../Films.html&quot;&gt;Films&lt;/a&gt;.  Next I will work on finishing the bibliographies - they are currently three-quarters complete.  However, I will be in and out of town over the next couple months, so this may not be complete until the summer.  </description>
      <enclosure url="http://bylochacon.com/History_Resources/Blog/Entries/2011/2/22_Commodity_and_Thematic_Histories_______%28%26_the_Links_are_Done%21%29_files/portuguese-wine-history-1.jpg" length="32495" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Foundations of the Modern World</title>
      <link>http://bylochacon.com/History_Resources/Blog/Entries/2011/2/17_Foundations_of_the_Modern_World.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">a725df4b-d46b-411a-b28b-6395e458b2f7</guid>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2011 11:03:35 -0800</pubDate>
      <description>&lt;a href=&quot;http://bylochacon.com/History_Resources/Blog/Entries/2011/2/17_Foundations_of_the_Modern_World_files/worldwide_percentage_of_adherents_by_religion_large.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://bylochacon.com/History_Resources/Blog/Media/worldwide_percentage_of_adherents_by_religion_large.png&quot; style=&quot;float:left; padding-right:10px; padding-bottom:10px; width:271px; height:172px;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The foundations mini-unit I used to teach at the start of my world history course each year involved a whirlwind overview of philosophies, religious systems, scientific thought and types of government.  The links I am putting here are for that purpose, not in-depth studies.  I have tried to put together a good collection, but of course I am not an expert in this field and would really appreciate thoughtful &lt;a href=&quot;Entries/2011/2/17_Foundations_of_the_Modern_World_files/mailto%253Abylochacon%2540gmail.com%253Fsubject%253DBylochacon.com%252520Suggestions&quot;&gt;input&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;../Links_Regarding_Intellectual_%2526_Ethical_Foundations_of_the_Modern_World.html&quot;&gt;Links Regarding Intellectual &amp;amp; Ethical Foundations of the Modern World&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="http://bylochacon.com/History_Resources/Blog/Entries/2011/2/17_Foundations_of_the_Modern_World_files/worldwide_percentage_of_adherents_by_religion_large.png" length="260598" type="image/png"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Ranking Is Up!</title>
      <link>http://bylochacon.com/History_Resources/Blog/Entries/2011/2/16_Google_Ranking_Is_Up%21.html</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">779e0152-58e1-4d7d-a2e5-57e87678b258</guid>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2011 10:35:45 -0800</pubDate>
      <description>&lt;a href=&quot;http://bylochacon.com/History_Resources/Blog/Entries/2011/2/16_Google_Ranking_Is_Up%21_files/google%20search%20Feb%2016%202011.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://bylochacon.com/History_Resources/Blog/Media/google%20search%20Feb%2016%202011_1.jpg&quot; style=&quot;float:left; padding-right:10px; padding-bottom:10px; width:271px; height:195px;&quot;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;I have now spent a year creating this site.  Six months ago, a search for “world history genocide teaching” put my site on google page twenty-five.  Today, it is on the first page, with only four sites above it.  Yay!&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Here’s a link to the search:&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/search%253Fq%253Dworld+history+genocide+teaching%2526ie%253Dutf-8%2526oe%253Dutf-8%2526aq%253Dt%2526rls%253Dorg.mozilla%253Aen-US%253Aofficial%2526client%253Dfirefox-a&quot;&gt;http://www.google.com/search?q=world+history+genocide+teaching&amp;amp;ie=utf-8&amp;amp;oe=utf-8&amp;amp;aq=t&amp;amp;rls=org.mozilla:en-US:official&amp;amp;client=firefox-a&lt;/a&gt;</description>
      <enclosure url="http://bylochacon.com/History_Resources/Blog/Entries/2011/2/16_Google_Ranking_Is_Up%21_files/google%20search%20Feb%2016%202011.jpg" length="175535" type="image/jpeg"/>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
